Poznań, Poland / Remote

in linkedin.com/in/yulios

github.com/YuliyaLios

B2B contract preferred

> COMPETENCES

- Technical writing:
 - Manuals.
 - API documentation,
 - How-To's,
 - User's Guide,
 - Release Notes,
 - Software Documentation
- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript basics
- Git / Github
- Manual testing
- API testing with Postman / Swagger
- XML, Markdown, JSON
- Jira, Confluence
- Proactivity
- Goal- and people-oriented
- Communication and interpersonal skills
- Responsibility and punctuality
- Commitment and determination
- The ability to transfer knowledge substantively and practically

> LANGUAGES

Ukrainian - nativeRussian - native

••••• **English** - B2/C1

••0000 **Polish** - A2 (learning)

JULIA KUZNIECOWA

Technical Writer, Technical Communicator, DocOps

Technical Writer with an engineering background.

Daily, I'm focused on creating developer docs, API specifications and user guides; first of all, interested in projects with a docs-as-code approach and DocOps strategy.

My professional interest lies widely in software development. As a specialist, I consider myself adaptable and detail-oriented, with excellent communication and creative thinking skills. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects and collaborate as part of a friendly team.

> EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer, Corefy, Remote

Aug 2019 - Present

- Developed and maintained documentation for external (clients) and internal (developers) users.
- Studied drawings, specifications, mockups and product samples to integrate and delineate technology, operating procedure, production sequence and detail.
- Interviewed production and engineering personnel to become familiar with product technologies and production methods.
- Standardised and made changes to material prepared by managers and developers.
- Selected photographs, drawings, and sketches and made diagrams and charts to illustrate the material.
- Provided manual testing, made interface localisation and helped develop software architecture documentation.

Head Of Content, Vintage Web Production, Kiyv, Ukraine

Sep 2017 – Jul 2019

- Reviewed and updated web pages' content.
- Administered Internet and intranet infrastructure, including Web, file and mail servers.
- Performed user testing and usage analyses to determine sites' effectiveness and usability.
- Gathered, analysed and documented user feedback to locate and resolve sources of problems.
- Collaborated with development teams to discuss, analyse and resolve usability issues.
- Provided training and technical assistance in Web site implementation and use.
- Documented installation or configuration procedures to allow maintenance and repetition.

> VOLUNTEERING

Girls.js Poland

2022.10 - Present Co-organizer JavaScript programming workshops introducing women to the IT field.

WWCode Kyiv

2019 - Present Education, inspiring and supporting women to excel in technology careers.

Kherson New Generation (NGO)

2000 - 2005

Children's Leadership Mentoring, Civil Rights and Social Action

Website Administrator, budcenter.net, Kiyv, Ukraine

Aug 2016 - Sep 2017

- Administered Internet and intranet infrastructure, including Web, file and mail servers.
- Reviewed or updated web pages' content. Tested issues such as system integration, performance and security on a regular schedule and after major program modifications.
- Provided manual testing, made interface localisation and helped develop software architecture documentation. Determined sources of web page or server problems and took action to correct problems.
- Identified and documented backup and recovery plans.

Engineer Estimator, Бизнес-Юрист, Donetsk, Ukraine

Sep 2009 - Nov 2012 Sep 2004 - Apr 2006

- Wrote and checked construction expertise reports.
- Calculated and verified civil building projects' estimates.
- Assessed the state of buildings and constructions.
- Provided consultation about existing regulatory and technical documentation.

> COURSES

Full Stack Web Development

freeCodeCamp, 2016

Web Development, Go FrontEnd program

GoIT, 2016

> EDUCATION

Industrial and Civil Engineering, B.E.

- Kherson State Agrarian University

2001 - 2009

I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for implementing the recruitment process according to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons concerning the processing of personal data and the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).